准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
宠物餐厅
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
餐点给
Order for--
恶心
Disgusting
你们人吃东西的样子像畜
You people eat like anima--
畜
anima--
Anima--
我的宝贝真乖
There's my baby
我的小宝贝
My little baby
不行
Oh, no
不能把虫子带到这里面来
You cannot bring a worm in here
非常不干净
It's unclean
我们当中有些人还过
And some of us are allergi
敏
gic
外面打喷嚏是怎么回事  章鱼哥先生
What's with all the sniffy fits out here, Mr. Squidward?
不是我的错  蟹老板
It's not my fault, Mr. Krabs
她偷偷把宠物带进蟹堡王里了
She snuck a pet into the restaurant
我都不知道我可爱的小菲菲不让进来
I didn't know my sweet little Fifi wasn't allowed
你可爱的小福福得走了
Well, your sweet little Foofoo's gotta go
我们有严格规定
We have a strict policy
宠物不可入内
No pets allowed
太可惜了
What a shame
我家菲菲这几天只吃蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties are all my Fifi will eat these days
我愿意付出双倍的价钱
I would have gladly paid double the price
只为了让菲菲能吃到最爱的食物
if it only meant she could have her favorite food
好了
There
完美解决
All fixed
看见没
See?
宠物可入内
"Now: Pets Allowed"
太高兴了
How delightful
果然
Of course
跟你说  章鱼哥先生
I tell ya, Mr. Squidward
我钱赚得都快比海神王还多了
I'm makin' more money than Neptune
先给我慢着  老螃蟹
Hold it right there, Krabs
不好了
Oh, no
是卫生检查员
The health inspector
非常好
Oh, yes
是卫生检查员
The health inspector
我很恐怕餐厅跟动物饲养场
And I'm afraid you can't run a restaurant and a feed lot
不能在同一座建筑里同时营业
out of the same building
卫生不过关
It's unsanitary
我要让你停业整顿
I'm shutting you down
除非你二选一
Unless you pick one
要选人  还是宠物
People or pets
人
宠物
好啊
Oh, yeah
就选宠物了
I choose pets
什么
What?
不行
No
好了  听见那位说的话了吧
All right, you heard the man
如果你不是宠物  那就算非法闯入
If you ain't a pet, you're trespassing
该走了
Time to go
动作快
Get a move on
等一下
Wait a minute
那我们宠物呢
What about our pets?
放心好了
Well, don't worry
宠物的餐费我还是会找你们要的
I'll still be billin' ya for whatever they eat
珊迪
Sandy
你家阿拉斯加牛虫实在挺饿的
Your Alaskan Bull Worm certainly was hungry
我的老天啊  我破产了
Sweet jawbone of San Antone, I'm broke
看来我后半年只能吃坚果罐头了
Looks like I'm eatin' canned nuts for the rest of the year
欢迎光临  小虫子
Welcome, little worm
来到蟹堡王  就是来到了宠物天堂
Here at the Krusty Krab, it's a pet paradise
玩得开心点
Enjoy yourself
别忘了点个餐来吃
And don't forget to order something to eat
还是我来帮你点餐吧
Maybe I'll order for you
老兄
Hey, man
我可不可以
Could I like
来份蟹黄堡打包外带
get a Krabby Patty to go?
抱歉
Sorry
本店仅服务宠物
Pets only
你可以到街对面去碰运气
You can try your luck across the street
我不想吃海霸糊
I don't wanna eat chum
海之霸
招牌菜
The house special
海霸糊
宠物能好好吃饭的确很好  可是
It's great that my pets are eating and all, but
我还是好饿
I'm still hungry
真希望我是只宠物
I wish I was a pet
这样我就能趴地上吃东西了
so I could eat off the floor
你现在就是在趴地上吃东西
You are eating off the floor
对啊  可是
Yeah, but--
我想趴地上吃蟹黄堡
I wanna eat Krabby Patties off the floor
那个粉家伙想到好办法了
The pink dude might have the right idea, guys
大家打扮成宠物
If we dress up like pets
就可以骗到蟹老板
We could trick Krabs
让他给咱提供服务了
into serving us
就这样
Of course
想做服装的话  我有个手工区
If you wanna make costumes, I have a craft corner
好啊
Oh, boy
手工美术
美术纸
Construction paper
好东西
Oh, boy
有谁看到胶水了吗
Anyone seen the glue?
胶水
现在正是大好机会
Now's my chance
可以让我躲我宠物点点里溜进蟹堡王
to sneak into the Krusty Krab in my pet, Spot
怎么回事
What's happening?
不行  点点
No, Spot
不要再消化我了  点点
Stop digesting me, Spot
坏点点
Bad Spot
真见鬼
Barnacles
进墙里去吧
Into the wall ya go
怎么
What the?
好啊
Oh, boy
我是说
I mean
好饿
Hungry
章鱼哥
Squidward
是  蟹
Yes, Mister--
老板
--Krabs
为什么宠物新客们
Why don't all these new pets
现在还吃不到蟹黄堡
have patties in front of 'em?
我办的可是生意  不是收容所
I'm running a business, not a shelter
你好啊  兔子朋友
Greetings, fellow lagomorph
你应该比较想分我一块
Perhaps you might consider sharing a sliver of your--
我就先
I'll just be
宠物大战
Pet fight
我的腿
My leg
不不不
No, no, no
坏扇贝
Bad scallops
谁准备好要
Who's ready for--
大打出手
a violent brawl?
大家住手
Stop, please
蟹堡王是和平友爱的地方
The Krusty Krab is a place of peace
卫生检查员
The health inspector?
可你不是说过
But I thought you said
人和宠物不能一起用餐吗
people and pets can't eat together?
对啊
Yeah
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
这团乱全都是你的错
This whole mess is your fault
我饿了  想来吃蟹黄堡
I was just hungry for a Krabby Patty
大家都这样对吧
We've all been there, right?
并且我
Plus, I, um
我今天也学到了不少
I learned something today
海绵宝宝  能不能来个快活的C大调
SpongeBob, give me a bouncy C, would ya?
好啊
Gladly
宠物  也是人
Pets are people too
与你我  一个样
Just like me, just like you
无论你们  爱做什么
Yes, whatever you like to do
总有宠物也一样爱
There's a pet who likes it too
有宠物能陪爱跑步的人
There's a pet for people who like to run
还有懒得动的人
And one for people who don't
有宠物能陪要遮阳的人
A pet for folks who avoid the sun
跟该遮却不遮的人
And those who should but won't
有宠物能陪人载歌载舞
A pet for people who sing and dance
有宠物能陪人哭
A pet for people who cry
有宠物能陪人冒险
A pet for people who take a chance
还能陪着个独眼
And for those with just one eye
无论大家说什么做什么
Yes, no matter what we say or do
总有件事我很认同
There's just one thing I know is true
大家特别爱吃蟹黄堡
We all eat patties, yes we do
每个宠物也一样爱吃
And every pet likes eating them too
因为
Because
宠物  也是人
Pets are people too
与你我  一个样
Just like me, just like you
无论你们  爱做什么
Yes, whatever you like to do
总有宠物能与你相像
There's a pet who's just like you
与你相像
Just like you
宠物
Pets
宠物和人应该要一起用餐
Pets and people deserve to eat side by side
好
Yes
蟹黄堡人人都有份
And a round of patties for everyone
不免费
Not on the house
天啊  先生
Gosh, mister
你们这里的顾客比我见过的都多
You've got more customers here than I've ever seen
那当然了
'Course I do
没听到刚才唱的吗
Didn't you hear the song?
宠物也是人
Pets are people too
要是它们也算人的话
Well if they count as people
那样它们也算火灾隐患
Then they count as fire hazards
我是消防局长
I'm the fire marshal
你的店已经严重超载  老螃蟹
and you're over capacity, Krabs
立刻关停
Shut her down
所有人都出去
Everyone out
什么
What?
不
No
等等
Wait
回来  回来
Come back, come back
我的宠物利润
Me pet profits
全都完蛋了
I'm ruined
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
我要把蟹黄堡带回家给小蜗吃
I was planning on taking a Krabby Patty home
to my Gare Bear
愿意的话多收我钱也行
You could overcharge me for it if you want
真的吗
Really?
谢了  小子
Thanks, boy-o
你这只领最低工资的员工可真好心
You're a good minimum wage employee
为爱封店
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
我飘到天上来了
I'm floating on air
坐热气球  烛光晚餐
A balloon ride, a candlelight dinner
还放着婚礼歌曲
and our wedding song is playing
这场约会太完美了
This date is perfect
完美的是你才对  凯伦
No, you're perfect, Karen
你是桡足类动物所能拥有的
You're the best computer wife
最棒的电脑老婆了
a copepod could ever have
吃个夹心糖
Bon bon?
不用了吧
I shouldn't
好好享受吧  亲爱的
Indulge yourself, my darling
裤头村
谢谢  痞老板
Thank you, Plankton
这场约会绝对永生难忘
This is truly a date to remember
亲爱的  真正的好戏你还没看到呢
Well, my love, you haven't seen anything yet
送你的  亲爱的
For you, my love
瑞瑞
Ray Ray
没错  宝贝
That's right, baby
瑞瑞为你效劳
Ray Ray is at your service
瑞瑞  你让我散热风扇转得好快
Ray Ray, you've got my cooling fans running on high
快过来  给我吻一个
Get over here and give me some sugar
好漫长的一天
What a long day
我受不了了
I can't take it
怎么了  痞老板
What is it, Plankton?
先等一下  宝贝
Hold that thought, baby
我
I uh--
我有东西忘在下面了
I forgot something down here
去去就回
I'll be right back
居然真的会有这种事
Can't believe this is really happening
蟹黄堡的秘密配方总算是我的了
The Krabby Patty secret formula is finally mine
我是不是在做噩梦
Is this some kind of horrible nightmare?
什么
What?
投影仪3000
投影仪
A projector?
你用模拟场景耍我
You tricked me with a simulation?
刚刚那是测试  痞老板
It was a test, Plankton
而你却没通过
And you failed
每次我们浪漫的时候你都出差错
You fail every time when it comes to our romance
对  所以说搞砸了这么一次
Right, so I goof up one time
就让我名誉扫地了
and now I'm the bad guy?
才一次
One time?
才搞砸了一次
Failed one time?
那之前四百七十万
How about 4,700,000 and
错误  错错错误
Error, er-er-error
可是宝贝
But baby cakes
我跑路是要去帮你偷蟹黄堡秘方
I left to go get the Krabby Patty secret formula
都是为了我
For me
也为了你
And you
你也知道
You know
为了我们
for us
听好  谢尔顿
Listen, Sheldon
你要给我好好来场不间断的约会之夜
You need to show me
an interruption-free romantic date night
约会没完整约完
because until that happens
就谁都不准踏出海之霸一步
no one is leaving the Chum Bucket
封店
你这回的约会最好别搞砸了  瑞瑞
You better not mess this one up, Ray Ray
凯伦最爱的电子废品炖汤
I think Karen's favorite "scrap electronics stew"
应该可以让她高兴
ought to do the trick
对
Yep
偷偷看一眼蟹堡王应该没什么大问题
I guess it wouldn't hurt to have
just a little peek at the Krusty Krab
好漫长的一天
What a long day
真的就在外面
It's really out there
而且这次还不是全息投影
And this time it's not a hologram
痞老板
Plankton
你在干什么
What are you doing?
宝贝
Hey, baby
只是在给今晚的主菜做点最后修饰
Just adding the finishing touches
to tonight's main course
你人真好
You are so sweet
我等不及要吃吃看了
I can't wait to try it
完美打圆场  痞老板
Good one, Plankton
秘方
The formula
我得怎么办才能偷到你呢
Now how am I gonna get you?
好好好
Yes, yes, yes
不不不
No, no, no
给我开慢点  你这疯子
Slow it down, you maniac
那是谁
Who's that?
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
是白痴派大星
It's that numbskull Patrick
大笨蛋
Hey, doofus
我是说  海星朋友
I mean, star friend
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
往这看
Over here
不对  往这看
No, over here
真是的
Come on
对  就这样
Yes, that's it
你看对地方了
You've got it
现在谁是乖孩子
Now who's a good boy?
好  把你脚边的瓶子拿过来
Okay, now grab that bottle by your feet there
不对
No
你脚边另外一个饮料盒
The other drink container by your feet
拿那个才对
Pick that one up instead
就在你脚边
By your feet
往右边看
Now look right
你一定是在逗我
You have got to be kidding me
往右  派大星
Right, Patrick
你另一个右边
Your other right
对
Yes
就是这样
That's it
乖孩子
Good boy
快带过来给我
Now bring it over here to me
对  就是这样
Yes, that's it
他到哪去了
Where did he go?
不好意思  你是擦窗户的吗
Excuse me, are you the window cleaner?
你到底怎么进来的
How in barnacles did you get in here?
不知道
I dunno?
谁在乎呢
Well, who cares?
我叫你带的瓶子你带来了吗
Did you bring that bottle I told you to bring?
味道有点怪
Tastes kinda funny, though
错了
No
我说的是另外一个  你个白痴
I said the other one, you moron
你们表现非常好
You guys are doing great
二三四
Two, three, four
我与我这世间最想要的东西之间
A thin piece of glass is all that stands
仅仅只是隔了一层薄薄的玻璃
between me and what I want most in the world
凭什么人生就是这么不公平
Why is life so unfair?
亲爱的
Honey?
晚餐做好了吗
Is dinner almost ready?
我都饿坏了
I'm famished
就快好了  甜心
It's almost finished, my sweetheart
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
痞老板  快想啊
Think, Plankton, think
想到了
Idea
就这样
That's it
凯伦肯定看不出哪不一样
Karen will never know the difference
能帮我大忙的东西就近在眼前
Now I think I got what I need right here
派大星  你可能会感觉有点痒
Patrick, you may feel a slight tickle
我就喜欢痒痒
I like tickles
好  来看看效果
Okay, let's get a look at this
好疼啊
That was intense
差点忘了
Almost forgot
你要跟我老婆凯伦约个会  瑞瑞
You're going on a date with my wife Karen, Ray Ray
可我声音很像派大星
But I sound like Patrick
不用你说
Oh, no
你把嘴闭上就行
You keep your mouth shut
交给我就行
I will take care of that
凯伦
Oh, Karen?
晚餐做好了  亲爱的
Dinner is served, my little love nugget
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh
品相也太好了
This looks amazing
我爱我的瑞瑞
I loves my Ray Ray
我也爱我的凯伦
And I love my Karen
开吃吧
Now let's dig in
蟹黄堡的秘密配方  我来了
Krabby Patty secret formula, here I come
感觉有点不舒服  瑞瑞
That's a little rough, Ray Ray
痞老板
Plankton
你在干什么
What are you doing?
感觉不错
That feels nice
好
Okay
晚安
Goodnight
好险啊
That was close
今天又是赚得盆满钵满的一天
Yep, we had another money stacking day
对不对啊
Didn't we--
我的蟹黄堡秘方
Me Krabby Patty secret formuler?
一定是从船上掉下去了
It must have fell out of me boat
别担心  甜心
Don't you worry, sweetie
老爸来救你了
Daddy's comin' for ya
秘方
Formuler
秘方  你在何方
Where are ye, formuler?
我秘方在哪
Where's me formuler?
你对我秘方干了什么好事
What have you done with me secret formuler?
秘方
Formuler?
你在哪
Where are ya?
秘方
Formuler?
Formuler
秘方
Formuler?
Formuler
你在哪  秘方
Where are you, formuler?
痞老板
Plankton
我知道你偷了我秘方
I know you have me formuler
快点交出来
So just hand it over
开门啊  痞老板
Open up, Plankton
我知道你偷了我秘方
I know you've got me formuler
谁在敲门
Who could that be?
那个嘣嘣的声音吗
That banging noise?
烘干机而已
That's just the dryer
衣服让我先洗了  等下就不用麻烦你了
I thought I'd do the laundry so you wouldn't have to later
亲亲
Kiss kiss
瑞瑞啊
Oh, Ray Ray
这可是你说过最浪漫的话了
That's the most romantic thing you've ever said
秘方总算是我的了
The formula is finally mine
快啊
Come on
我知道你在里面  痞老板
I know you're in there, Plankton
什么
Wha?
秘方
Formula
谢谢你帮我拿着
Thanks for holding it for me
是我的
It's mine
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
今天弥补了一切
Today made up for everything
所以我想给你点东西
So I wanted to give you a little something
经过多年来的调查
After years of research
我最终综合了数据
I finally synthesized the data
生成了蟹黄堡的秘密配方
and came up with the Krabby Patty secret formula
痞老板
Plankton
放手
Let go
行啊  老螃蟹
Whatever you say, Krabs
谁还用得着你的瓶装纸质版
Who needs your stupid hard copy in a bottle, anyway
我现在都有可以下载的电子版了
when I have a downloadable version right here?
你个浑蛋
You jerk
现在
Now
秘密配方就是
the secret formula is
是什么
Is what?
秘方是什么
What is it?
瑞瑞
Ray Ray
我们哪一个是瑞瑞
Which one of us is Ray Ray?
我才是  你个白痴
I am, you doofus
那
Well
那我也是瑞瑞
well, I'm Ray Ray too
不对  我才是瑞瑞
No, I'm Ray Ray
我不稀罕谁才是真瑞瑞
I don't care who is the real one
你们俩都得亲眼看我删掉秘方
You can both watch this formula get deleted
凯伦
Karen
亲爱的  甜心
Darling, sweetie
有话好好说
Please, let's talk about this
已删除
别搞砸约会之夜  痞老板
Don't mess with date night, Plankton
现在这才是上好的约会  痞老板
Now this is truly a wonderful date, Plankton
谢谢你把注意力全集中在我身上
And thank you for giving me your undivided attention
无论如何我都会跟你好好浪漫  宝贝
I wouldn't miss it for the world, baby
天啊
Oh, boy